<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>FunBlocks</title>
 <link href="http://stefanj.me/funblocks/funblocks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://stefanj.me/funblocks/funblocks/"/>
 <updated>2016-06-01T21:30:02+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://stefanj.me/funblocks</id>
 <author>
   <name>Stefan Jacholke</name>
   <email>stefanjacholke@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello Blockly</title>
   <link href="http://stefanj.me/funblocks/2016/05/28/hello-blockly/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://stefanj.me/funblocks/funblocks/2016/05/28/hello-blockly</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockly&quot;&gt;Blockly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officially, HSOC projects start from the 13th June. This provides time 
to do some research. Today I decided to take a look at Blockly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up Blockly is rather straightforward. I cloned Blockly as a 
git submodule.
I created a simple HTML page with a Blockly canvas. Setting up
Blockly involves &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/blockly/guides/configure-blockly/web/fixed-size&quot;&gt;creating a static sized div and loading the
javascript&lt;/a&gt;.
Later I will set it up as a resizable workspace.
Blockly comes with a javascript CodeGen, later I will have to 
implement a
Haskell/CodeWorld CodeGen for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;codeworld&quot;&gt;CodeWorld&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the advice on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/codeworld/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; I 
created a new codeworld Linux user account and
went on to set up CodeWorld.
The current build script for CodeWorld covers the zypper, apt-get and yum
package managers. 
Running Arch I’ve got pacman. I already had most the required packages 
(git, zlib, ncurses, gcc, gmp, patch, autoconf, automake, openssl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was missing was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pacman -S npm nodejs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had GHC 7.10.3 and cabal already installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing GHCJS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/ghcjs/ghcjs.git
cabal install ./ghcjs
ghcjs-boot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and also ghcjs-dom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cabal install ghcjs-dom
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have the cabal bin in my PATH so I needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;export PATH=/home/codeworld/.cabal/bin:$PATH
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before running the standard CodeWorld build script. After running 
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run.sh&lt;/code&gt; started up the web server. 
Everything ran fine, minus saving projects, which I did not set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ghcjs&quot;&gt;GHCJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to play around with GHCJS as well, having never used it 
before.
Documentation was rather scarce but I managed to put together a simple 
hello world application; with a compiled js file of about 43KLOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the sample programs found were using an old version of 
GHCJS-DOM. I will return to GHCJS when I start programming on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-testing&quot;&gt;Testing, testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal today was to quickly set a simple page containing Blockly and 
a CodeWorld application as a simple test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a simple HTML file with Bootstrap for minimal styling, added 
Blockly and an iframe for running a standard CodeWorld application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the example Snap site comprises of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;module Main where

import Control.Applicative
import Snap.Core
import Snap.Http.Server
import Snap.Util.FileServe
import Snap.Util.FileUploads
import System.Directory
import System.FilePath

main :: IO ()
main = quickHttpServe site

site :: Snap ()
site =
        ifTop (writeBS &quot;hello world&quot;) &amp;lt;|&amp;gt;
        route [ (&quot;foo&quot;, writeBS &quot;bar&quot;)
               ,(&quot;echo/:echoparam&quot;, echoHandler)
               ] &amp;lt;|&amp;gt;
        serveDirectory &quot;web&quot;


echoHandler :: Snap ()
echoHandler = do
    param &amp;lt;- getParam &quot;echoparam&quot;
    maybe (writeBS &quot;must specify echoparam in URL&quot;)
          writeBS param
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the server looking for a page to serve from “web” if it does not 
match any of the routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally wanted to send a code sample from the FunBlocks page to 
the locally hosted CodeWorld server with a XMLHttpRequest, however, this I could not do 
as the FunBlocks site and CodeWorld server were on different ports, thus I ended up receiving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;XMLHttpRequest cannot load. No &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; header is 
present on the requested resource.
Origin is therefore not allowed access
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as an error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to mess around with headers I decided to just copy over
the codeworld-server files and serve the same resources, with the new 
index page as an addition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually only wanted the compile and run features for this simple 
test. 
So currently the server is exactly the same as the codeworld-server 
with a modified codeworld.js and custom index.
This makes things easy as FunBlocks can be hosted together with 
CodeWorld later, just on a different page.
I would enjoy having a solid implementation for the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts on a good approach to take with this are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;type-checking-and-an-intermediate-form&quot;&gt;Type checking and an intermediate form.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flow of the language will be something similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blocks -&amp;gt; Intermediate code representation -&amp;gt; CodeGen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intermediate code representation should cover a basic set of 
features of
Haskell, enough to be able to generate valid CodeWorld applications. 
User friendliness is also a concern, since the project is 
educationally focussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks should snap properly and maybe display suitable error
messages otherwise. For this to occur however, some form of type 
checking will have to be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gathered some resources which I will look at later:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cecs.pdx.edu/~mpj/thih/&quot;&gt;Typing Haskell in Haskell&lt;/a&gt; - 
Haskell type checking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hackage.haskell.org/package/hint-0.5.2&quot;&gt;Hint&lt;/a&gt; - Type-check 
and evaluate strings with Haskell expressions and even coerce them 
into values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Books/ProgLangs/2007-04-26/&quot;&gt;Programming 
languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming languages, covers Racket, has got a chapter on type 
checking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/simonpj/papers/slpj-book-1987/&quot;&gt;The Implementation of Functional Programming 
Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contains a chapter on Polymorphic type checking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hackage.haskell.org/package/baskell&quot;&gt;Baskell&lt;/a&gt; - A small 
functional language featuring type inference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest might be to rely on Hint to type check Haskell expressions 
and do some backtracing, this avoids having to implement type inference. 
Though if time allows I might be tempted to do a proper implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most CodeWorld functions are monomorphic and have concrete types, with 
some exceptions (simulations). So some part of CodeWorld can be implemented 
without worrying too much about type checking, however, I would enjoy having a 
solid implementation for the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts on a good approach to take with this are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World</title>
   <link href="http://stefanj.me/funblocks/2016/05/24/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://stefanj.me/funblocks/funblocks/2016/05/24/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, first off, I got accepted into &lt;a href=&quot;https://summer.haskell.org/&quot;&gt;Haskell Summer of Code 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The project is
to develop a visual functional block based langauge for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.world/&quot;&gt;CodeWorld&lt;/a&gt;, under &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdsmith.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Chris Smith&lt;/a&gt;. 
The project is in the same vein as Scratch, although it will be based on functional principles which will be a subset of Haskell. 
The project idea is described more fully in the &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/05/23/project-proposal/&quot;&gt;Project Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the other goals of this site include me tracking progress of the project and interacting with the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a graduate student studying Computer and Electronic Engineering and aside from Summer of Code reasons for doing the project, I’m also interested in
programming languages (and obviously Haskell) and hope to learn a good deal through doing such a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I’m also explicitly giving permission to be included on Planet Haskell&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Project Proposal</title>
   <link href="http://stefanj.me/funblocks/2016/05/23/project-proposal/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://stefanj.me/funblocks/funblocks/2016/05/23/project-proposal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;visual-functional-block-based-programming-language-for-codeworld&quot;&gt;Visual functional block-based programming language for CodeWorld&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/coeFzag.png&quot; alt=&quot;blockly&quot; title=&quot;blockly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to develop a functional-based visual blocks-based programming language, similar to Scratch and other languages, that is based on a subset of Haskell.
The project will extend CodeWorld and will use its API. The project will feature a user interface to allow the user to snap, drag and drop blocks in order to construct CodeWorld programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language will be a prototype as a full language is beyond the current scope and timeframe. Future work and stretch goals are presented as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is an extension to CodeWorld, which is an educational web-based programming environment
A visual language is a great way to get students started with programming and a functional language might be well suited to such composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outline&quot;&gt;Outline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-interface&quot;&gt;User interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of a friendly user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A user-friendly interface will be designed and implemented&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap or a similar HTML/CSS framework will be used to design the interface. The user interface logic will be implemented using Javascript and Jquery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user interface of the project will utilize &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/blockly/&quot;&gt;Blockly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockly will be adapted to match the functional style and various blocks will be created in order to match the CodeWorld API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;generator&quot;&gt;Generator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haskell code generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockly applications turn blocks into code in order to execute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The project will generate valid Haskell CodeWorld programs from the blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The code generation will be done using GHCJS with an intermediate block language layer handling the visual language before generating valid CodeWorld code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blocks&quot;&gt;Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each shape represents a type. A block (that consists of a shape) will have multiple slots or parameters into which other blocks can be inserted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow creation of top-level definition blocks / functions than can be reused. A separate tab/panel for construction of definitions will be available in the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;validation-and-error-messages&quot;&gt;Validation and Error messages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Validation and verification of a valid program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure only valid programs can be constructed. Blocks should only be able to be connected if their types match.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If snapping does not occur, visually tell the user why (tell them what type was expected, if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If an error does occur it should be displayed in a friendly manner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When hovering over a slot it should display what input type is expected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blocks should indicate their output type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;polymorphic-types&quot;&gt;Polymorphic types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some blocks will have to handle polymorphic types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blocks may have multiple slots; if a slot gets connected the other slots might change color if the are the same type. 
For example, if we have an IF (condition) (consequence) (alternative) block then when either consequence or alternative is connected the other slot should reflect the same type.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blocks might also change color to reflect their type.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimal handling of polymorphic types will be included in order to accommodate CodeWorld’s API. Complete integration is seen as a stretch goal (if time allows).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User data can be constructed from a set of basic types. Constructors and destructors will allow manipulations of the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;codeworld-integration&quot;&gt;CodeWorld integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blocks to reflect CodeWorld functions and data types, such that CodeWorld programs can be built.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most CodeWorld functions are monomorphic, however, simulations require a polymorphic state/world type. We propose that such data types be constructed from existing primitive types using constructors and destructors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-might-need-to-be-excluded&quot;&gt;What might need to be excluded&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom algebraic data types. Since blocks are predefined there may not be a way to extract data from a user-defined data type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekly communication will be made with the mentor to ensure the project is on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before June 12&lt;/strong&gt; - Research into current visual block-based programming languages such as Scratch, what good ideas they utilize and what can be carried over to this project. Research into some of the current problems that a functional based visual programming language faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 12th&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Deliverable&lt;/em&gt; - Mock up design of the user interface. Overview of what blocks might be supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 13th - June 30th&lt;/strong&gt; - Design of the functional block based language. Set up of CodeWorld and Blockly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 1st - July 30th&lt;/strong&gt; - Setup of a basic interface, incorporate Blockly and interface with CodeWorld. Discover and overcome unsuspected challenges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 31st&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Deliverable&lt;/em&gt; - Basic user interface set up. A basic program should be able to built using the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 1st - August 15th&lt;/strong&gt; - Implement Codeworld functions and types. Complete Blockly code generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 16th&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Deliverable&lt;/em&gt; - CodeWorld example programs should be able to be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 16th - September 2nd&lt;/strong&gt; - Polish user interface, improve error messages, fix bugs. Some leeway for the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have limited availability from 4 - 7 September due to a conference. It does not seem to interfere with any important dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will communicate with my mentor if there are any other difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stretch-goals&quot;&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time allows and a good solution presents itself the following may be implemented (but is not part of the core project), otherwise they are presented as good ideas for future versions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pattern Matching&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for ADT’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for editing list comprehensions, live previews of list comprehensions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full recursion support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First class functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Stefan Jacholke&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;University&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;NWU Potchefstroom&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Course&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;M.Eng Computer&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Degree&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;B.Eng Computer and Electronic&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Email&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;stefanjacholke@gmail.com&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Github&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stefan-j&quot;&gt;https://github.com/stefan-j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a first-year computer engineering graduate student at NWU in South Africa, studying Network Optimization and Planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current interests include Programming Languages, Algorithms, and Data structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have only recently started developing in Haskell I have used it for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing my own simple programming language&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed a simple math expression simplifier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Am currently developing a mobile coffee purchases mobile application; the backend for the application is written in Haskell (that handles credit card purchases, queries to the POS system, interface between app and
  database)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using Haskell for algorithmic problems (HackerRank, Codejam)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stefan-j/cplex-haskell&quot;&gt;FFI binding to interface with CPLEX&lt;/a&gt; (commercial linear programming solver)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using it to develop my framework for Metro Ethernet optimization  (Master’s project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experience in Web development, mostly through some of my pregraduate
courses. In particular, I have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed a Real Estate web site for advertisements using ASP.NET, MySQL, and ReactJS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed a File management site for uploading and downloading files (similar to dropbox, though simpler) using PHP, Bootstrap and Jquery and AJAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various experience with other technologies (though unrelated to project at hand). I also have a few other projects in different languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some small open source contributions listed on my Github profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information can be given on request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is based on Chris Smith’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/codeworld/issues/85&quot;&gt;proposal for a block-based UI for CodeWorld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
